99percentinvisible.org 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - 99% Invisible

**PLEASE READ THIS 99% INVISIBLE INC. PRIVACY POLICY (“PRIVACY POLICY”) WHICH IS PART OF THE 99% INVISIBLE INC. TERMS OF USE (“TERMS OF USE”) CAREFULLY. ANY TERMS DEFINED IN THE TERMS OF USE SHALL HAVE THE SAME MEANING IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. THIS PRIVACY POLICY PERTAINS TO YOUR ACCESSING AND USING THE SERVICE, INCLUDING BY USING THE WEBSITES AND ALL CONTENT AVAILABLE THROUGH THE WEBSITES.**

The Service is operated by 99% Invisible Inc. (“We”). This Privacy Policy describes the information collected during Your use of the Service, how We use it, how We share it, how We protect it, and the choices You can make about Your information.

ATTENTION: PLEASE READ OUR PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE DOWNLOADING FROM OR USING THE SERVICE. DOWNLOADING FROM OR USING THE SERVICE INDICATES THAT YOU ACCEPT AND AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY IN FULL. IF YOU DO NOT ACCEPT THIS PRIVACY POLICY, DO NOT DOWNLOAD FROM OR USE THE SERVICE.

You acknowledge (a) that You have read and understood this Privacy Policy; and (b) this Privacy Policy shall have the same force and effect as a signed agreement. Unless explicitly stated otherwise, any new features that augment or enhance the current Service shall be subject to this Privacy Policy. Please review the Privacy Policy each time You use the Service. BY USING THE SERVICE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THE MOST RECENT VERSION OF THE PRIVACY POLICY. If We materially change this Privacy Policy, We’ll let You know by showing it to You again when You access the Service.

## I. Information We Collect

We collect information from You when You use the Service, sign up to receive our newsletter, post User Submissions, contact or interact with us, fill out a form, and voluntarily provide us with Your comments and other content in connection with using the Service.

When You sign up to receive our newsletter, We collect your email address. When you submit information through our contact form or post comments to the Service, We collect your name, email address, and any other information that You provide to us.

You may use some portions of the Service anonymously, though We automatically collect information regarding each user of our Service, including the domain name of Your Internet search provider, Your IP address, the Service features You use and the time of Your use, location-based information, Your device ID, Your device information (e.g. device model and operating system version), the website address of a site through which you accessed a link to the Service, and aggregated information that cannot be used to specifically identify You when You use the Service.

We may collect information about You from third party sources including, but not limited to, podcast hosting providers, analytics services, email and contact management services, and advertisers.

We may combine all of the information we collect from or about You and use it in the manner described in this Privacy Policy.

## II. How We Use Your Information

We use the information that We collect for several purposes, including:

  * The purposes for which You provided it;
  * To provide services to You;
  * To process and respond to Your inquiries and comments;
  * To send You information about Your relationship or transactions with us;
  * To develop new products and services;
  * To personalize and enhance Your experience using the Service;
  * To generate and review reports and data about our user base and service usage patterns;
  * To compile aggregate data for internal and external business purposes;
  * To display relevant advertising;
  * To prevent fraud and abuse of the Service and to otherwise protect users and visitors and our business;
  * To assist law enforcement and respond to subpoenas;
  * To administer, operate and improve the Service and for internal business purposes; and
  * To perform other business activities as needed, or as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.
  * As explained elsewhere in this Privacy Policy, personal information We collect may be processed by our partners in providing related services to the Service (such as email newsletters, podcast hosting, technical services relating to the maintenance, servicing, and upgrading of software, hosting services, data migration services and analytical services, among others).

## III. How Your Information is Disclosed

Information may be disclosed to third parties in accordance with our Privacy Policy. Please note that a user may choose not to share certain information as described in Your Choices Regarding Your Information below.

**A. Third Party Service Providers and Business Partners.**

We may use third party service providers and business partners to perform functions in connection with the Service, such as email management, podcast hosting, site analytics and functions related to analyzing and improving the Service usefulness, reliability, user experience, and operation, advertising, storing data, providing users with products and services, and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.

**B. Business Changes.**

If We become involved in a merger, acquisition, sale of assets, joint venture, securities offering, bankruptcy, reorganization, liquidation, dissolution, or other transaction or if the ownership of all or substantially all of our business otherwise changes, We may transfer Your information to a third party or parties in connection therewith.

**C. Investigations and Law.**

We may disclose information about You to third parties if We believe that such disclosure is necessary to:

  * Investigate fraud and abuse on the Service;
  * Take action regarding suspected illegal activities;
  * Enforce or apply this Privacy Policy or other agreements with us;
  * Comply with the law or guidance and cooperate with government or law enforcement officials or private parties;
  * Protect our rights, reputation, safety, and property, or that of users or others;
  * Respond to claims and legal process (for example, subpoenas); and/or
  * Protect against legal liability.

**D. Aggregated Information.**

We may share aggregated information relating to users of the Service with affiliated or unaffiliated third parties. This aggregated information does not contain personal information about any user.

**E. Analytics.**

We use Google Analytics and other third-party analytics providers to better understand who is using the Service and how people are using it. Analytics providers, including but not limited to Google Analytics, Podtrac, and Rawvoice, Inc. (Blubrry) may use cookies, pixel tags, and other technologies to collect and store information such as website pages visited, places where users click, time spent on each website page, podcasts downloaded, domain name of a user’s Internet search provider, IP address, device model, type of operating system used, location-based data, website address from a site through which a user accessed a link to the Service, and device ID. We use this information to improve the Service and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. Please see http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/ for information about how Google Analytics uses this information, and visit https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout for information about the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on. Google Analytics and other third-party analytics providers may track you over time and across websites or applications.

## IV. Cookies, Local Storage, and Other Tracking Technologies

Cookies are small files that a website or its service provider transfers to Your computer’s hard drive through Your Web browser (if You allow it) that enable the website’s or service provider’s system to recognize Your browser and capture and remember certain information. You can instruct Your browser to stop accepting cookies. But if You do not accept cookies, You may not be able to use all portions of all functionality of the Service.

  * Persistent cookies remain on the visitor’s computer after the browser has been closed.
  * Session cookies exist only during a visitor’s online session and disappear from the visitor’s computer when they close the browser software.
  * We may deliver advertisements to You. We may work with third-party advertising companies that help deliver these advertisements to You. To learn more about third-party online advertising and to opt out of certain types of advertising, please see http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp. Note that clearing cookies from Your browser will remove the above opt-outs because they are stored in cookies.

We use cookies on the Service to help us understand and save Your preferences and interests so We can personalize Your future visits and compile aggregate data about website traffic and website interaction so that We can offer better website experiences and tools in the future. Some of our business partners, such as our analytics providers, also use cookies and other technologies on our Websites, some of which may track users across websites and over time.

## V. Security

We implement a variety of security measures to protect the safety of Your personal information when You enter, submit, or access Your personal information. While We take reasonable measures to protect the information You submit via the Service against loss, theft and unauthorized use, disclosure, or modification, We cannot guarantee its absolute security. No Internet, email, or mobile application transmission is ever fully secure or error free. Email or other messages sent through the Service may not be secure. You should use caution whenever submitting information through the Service and take special care in deciding with which information You provide us.

We cannot guarantee that transmissions of your personal information will be fully secure and that third parties will never be able to defeat our security measures or the security measures of our service providers. WE ASSUME NO LIABILITY FOR DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION DUE TO TRANSMISSION ERRORS, THIRD-PARTY ACCESS OR CAUSES BEYOND OUR CONTROL.

## VI. Data Retention Policy, Managing Your Information

We will retain Your information for as long as You use the Service and for a reasonable time thereafter. Please note that some or all of the information We have collected may be required in order for the Service to function properly.

## VII. Links to Other Websites or Applications

This Privacy Policy applies only to the Service. The Service may contain links to other websites or apps or may forward users to other websites or apps that We may not own or operate. The links from the Service do not imply that We endorse or have reviewed these websites or apps. The policies and procedures We describe here do not apply to these websites or apps. We neither can control nor are responsible for the privacy practices or content of these websites or apps. We suggest contacting these websites or app providers directly for information on their privacy policies. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our Service and welcome any feedback about these linked websites and mobile applications.

## VIII. Your Choices Regarding Your Information

You have choices regarding the use of information by the Service.

**Changing Your Information**

To change Your information or subscription options, check any newsletter you have received from the site for options to either completely unsubscribe or modify your preferences.

**Unsubscribing**

You may unsubscribe from the Service by clicking a link in your copy of our email newsletter. If the email account associated with Your email address is not active, We may remove your subscription without notice.

## IX. Information Collected From Other Websites and Mobile Applications, and Do Not Track Policy

Through cookies We place on Your browser or device, We and our marketing partners may collect information about Your online activity after You leave the Service. Just like any other usage information We collect, this information allows us to improve the Service and customize Your online experience, and otherwise as described in this privacy policy. Your browser may offer You a “Do Not Track” option, which allows You to signal to operators of websites and mobile applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that You do not wish such operators to track certain of Your online activities over time and/or across different websites and mobile applications and services. The Service does not support Do Not Track requests at this time, which means that We collect information about Your online activity both while You are using the Service and after you leave the Service.

## X. Children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from an individual under age 13. If You are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal information through the Service. If You have reason to believe that We may have accidentally received personal information from an individual under age 13, please contact us immediately at contact@99pi.org or 99% Invisible 1714 Franklin Street #100-335 Oakland, CA 94612-3409

.

## XI. Terms and Conditions

Please also visit the 99% Invisible Terms of Use at 99percentinvisible.org/terms, which state the terms, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing Your use of the Service.

## XII. Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time. Please review this Privacy Policy periodically, and especially before You provide any information. This Privacy Policy was made effective on the date indicated above.

## XIII. How to Contact Us

Please feel free to contact us by email at contact@99pi.org or by writing us at 99% Invisible 1714 Franklin Street #100-335 Oakland, CA 94612-3409 if You have any questions about this Privacy Policy.

## XIV. Your California Privacy Rights

Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code permits California residents to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information about the types of personal information the business has shared with third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes and the names and addresses of the third parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding calendar year. You may make one request each year by emailing us at contact@99pi.org or by writing us at 99% Invisible 1714 Franklin Street #100-335 Oakland, CA 94612-3409.
